SEAN SWANSONFRONT-END JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER

Summary

I am an optimistic front leaning, full-stack web developer obsessed with beauty, design, and functional tech. My passions lie in building and designing beautiful and wicked-fast applications that connect us to our humanity and drive change. The education I sought in philosophy, history in leadership, and time spent practicing the arts places me at an intersection that informs how I approach my role as a builder and a designer in the modern digital ecosystem.

Skills

Semantically Written HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript/ES6, jQuery, Responsive Design & CSS Frameworks, JSON, RESTful APIs, MERN-Stack, MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Git, Github, PostgreSQL, React Native

Projects

Chairman of the Board

A humorous & retro corporate ladder simulator game, à la Oregon Trail. Inspiration came from a game my father programmed in GW Basic back in the 80's with the aim of creating a fun, tongue-in-cheek, learning experience for young adults.

I designed and built Chairman of the Board with:

- > HTML5 > CSS3
- > JavaScript/jQuery

mndf.ll

A full-stack daily journal and goal tracking app for cultivating an enriched life featuring user auth, external API, and database utilization. I took this project as an opportunity to build out and design the functionality of a component I will be integrating into a larger pet project.

I designed and built mndf.ll with:

- > PostgreSQL > Express
- > EJS Templating Engine
- > Node.js > CSS3 with Materialize

Hue

A MERN-stack color detection utility for designers featuring cloud uploading and asynchronous operations created by myself, Jade Rosse, Desiree Rainey. The idea behind Hue came from my frequent use and reverence (seriously, color schemes are underappreciated) of similar utilities found online like Adobe Color or Palleton.

We designed and built Hue using these technologies:

- > MongoDB with Mongoose > Express
- > React.js with React Router, React Dom, etc.,
- > Node.js > CSS3

PokèDex

A PEN-stack Pokémon encyclopedia as a study of RESTful API architecture and artistic design.

Some technologies used for this project were:

- > PostgreSQL > Express
- → Node.js → EJS → CSS3

Contact

- **■** seancswan@gmail.com
- seancswanson.com
- **425)458-8778**
- **♀** Seattle, WA
- in seancswanson
- seanthaswan

Education

General Assembly

Full-Stack Web Development 2018 480+ hour immersive coding bootcamp program dedicated to creating full stack web applications.

Agile, project-based development primarily using the MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express JS, React JS, Node JS) both individually and with a team.

University of Washington

B.A. Philosophy 2015

Concentration in ethics, metaphysics, and philosophy of art (aesthetics).

Bellevue College

A.A. 2013

Employment

DERU Market

Kirkland, WA Mar 2014 to Nov 2017

Hospitality Specialist Mar 2014 to Nov 2017
Server/Maitre'd at chef-prepared, farm-totable restaurant. Cultivated strong leadership
and team building skills imperative to
succeed in it's very fast-paced and highvolume environment. Created and
maintained strong client relationships in
virtue of our mission statement.

TCM Models

Fashion Model

International Sep 2012 to Current

Represented also by State MGMT / Major Models:

Runway, Fashion Editorial, Fitness board model.